[
    {
        "question": "How do I know if I need to declare my manpower details?",
        "answer": "As part of the Phase 2 Heightened Alert announced on 16 May 2021, all firms are required to declare your onsite manpower details (https://go.gov.sg/covidbusinessresumptions) under the reference number starting with MPsubmit. Please refer to this (/guides/) for instructions on how to do so. Firms are required to make your declarations by 28 May 2021.",
        "start": [],
        "end": [
            "28 May 2021"
        ],
        "day_of": [
            "16 May 2021"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "I had declared my onsite manpower previously under another reference number. Do I need to make any changes to that even as I am now instructed to declare my onsite manpower under the reference number starting with \"\"MPsubmit-\"\"?",
        "answer": "There is no need to edit the manpower declaration in other reference number(s). From 24 May 2021, you will only need to declare your on-site manpower under the MPsubmit- reference.",
        "start": [
            "24 May 2021"
        ],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "How do I declare my manpower details?",
        "answer": "Please login (https://go.gov.sg/covidbusinessresumptions). Thereafter, please click on the button submit manpower to submit your manpower details.",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "How do I calculate the total no. of manpower working on-site?",
        "answer": "This refers to the total number of employees working on-site (i.e. no longer working from home).",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "How do I calculate the maximum number of workers on-site at any time?",
        "answer": "This refers to the maximum number of workers on site at any given time (after taking into account shift work/split team arrangements/part-time).",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "I am unable to declare my manpower details. What should I do?",
        "answer": "Please refer to this (/guides/) for instructions on how to declare your manpower details. If you continue to face any issues declaring your manpower details, please contact (mailto:COVID_GoBusiness@mti.gov.sg) for assistance.",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "How long do I need to keep declaring/submitting my manpower details? Do I need to update this information on a daily basis whenever there are changes to my manpower count?",
        "answer": "You will be expected to ensure that your manpower details are updated regularly. Any significant changes to the manpower count or manpower details which you had declared earlier should be updated as soon as possible.",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Can I proceed to operate after declaring/submitting my manpower details? Will I receive any notification of approval?",
        "answer": "You will receive an email acknowledgment of your manpower declaration. In the meantime, you may continue to operate if your business activities fall within MTIs list of permitted services or you have a General Exemption approval to operate onsite. You must adhere to all the relevant safe management measures for your sector.",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "What happens if I do not receive an acknowledgement email after I have declared my manpower details?",
        "answer": "If you have not received an acknowledgement email, your email address may be inaccurately captured on our system. For applicants with a Corppass account, kindly login (https://go.gov.sg/covidbusinessresumptions) to verify that your email address is accurately reflected.",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Is there a limit to the number of times I can change my manpower declaration details?",
        "answer": "You may change and resubmit your manpower declaration up to 5 times a day. Each new submission will override all previous submissions.",
        "start": [],
        "end": [
            "5 times"
        ],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Is there a cap on the number of workers allowed on site?",
        "answer": "No. However, businesses are required to implement work-from-home as a default and only workers whose work cannot be performed at home are allowed to continue to work on site.",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "If my workers are deployed at other premises and not working at my own business premise, do I include them in the onsite manpower declaration?",
        "answer": "Workers who are not working from home should be counted, i.e. your count of workers should include",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Do I need to submit my manpower details if my business premise is my place of residence?",
        "answer": "If your registered business premise is your place of residence, you can submit manpower as 0.",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Will enforcement officers check against the number of people my company have declared to work onsite?",
        "answer": "In relation to the safe management measure on work-from-home, enforcement officers will review whether the role of the worker who is working onsite cannot be performed from home.",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Why is the manpower submission requirement for Marine & Offshore and Process sectors different?",
        "answer": "From 1 July 2020, businesses that falls under the Marine & Offshore and Process sectors will be required to submit details of the employees/workers (https://foodservices.gobusiness.gov.sg/exemptions/login). This submission of manpower details is required to facilitate information updates for the AccessCode on the SGWorkPass app, including the approval to work and the requirement for regular swabbing. Failure to do so will cause the employees SGWorkPass AccessCode status to reflect as Red.",
        "start": [
            "1 July 2020"
        ],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "What manpower details must I submit, and from when should I be submitting?",
        "answer": "You will need to submit the FIN/NRICs of your workers/employees that are working on-site, and the maximum number of workers on site at any given time. If your workers are working on-site, you will also need to provide the address of the work premises, and indicate whether the work premises is a production site (e.g. shipyards/ production plant) or non-production site (e.g. other workplaces/ office premise). Please note that workers deployed at production sites will be required to undergo <strong>Rostered Routine Testing (RRT)</strong>.",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "What is considered a production site?",
        "answer": "Production site is defined as areas where shipbuilding/ship repair, process maintenance and construction activities are carried out. Examples of production sites includes shipyards, process plants, refineries and fabrication workshops.",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "If my office is located within my production site, how should I indicate so in my manpower submission?",
        "answer": "If the office staff do not come into contact with the production site workers and are clearly segregated, you can indicate your premises as a non-production site.",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "If my worker/employees are deployed across multiple sites, how do I indicate so when submitting my manpower details?",
        "answer": "You will need to click on the Add Premises button to key in the details of your workers/employees that are deployed across multiple sites.",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "If my company has multiple work premises, do I need to submit manpower details for all my workers across all the different work premises?",
        "answer": "You will need to click on the Add Premises button to key in the details of all your companys work premises.",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Will I receive any additional notification to know whether my worker/employee is approved to work on-site? How do I know if my submitted manpower is approved to work on-site?",
        "answer": "Upon submission of the manpower details, you will receive an email acknowledgement. The AccessCode on SGWorkPass app will determine whether your submitted manpower is allowed to work on site. The AccessCode will factor in a few parameters, namely:",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "By when should I submit my manpower details to know whether my worker/employee will be allowed to work on-site?",
        "answer": "You will need to submit your manpower details by 1730 hours, for your worker/employees AccessCode to be updated by 2359 hours on the following day via the SGWorkPass app.",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "What happens if the employee/workers AccessCode is not updated?",
        "answer": "If you have submitted your manpower details by 1730 hours, your employee/workers AccessCode will only be updated by 2359 hours on the following day. If you require assistance, please write to MTI at (mailto:covid_gobusiness@mti.gov.sg).",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "When do I need to update my manpower details submission?",
        "answer": "You will need to update your manpower details as soon as there is a change in the specific workers required to work on-site, as this will affect arrangements for your workers regular swab tests.",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "My SSIC code is in Marine/Offshore/Process but that is not the nature of my work. Do I still have to submit my manpower details?",
        "answer": "Manpower details are required for companies utilising Marine Shipyard or Process manpower quota as defined under MOM. These details are required to ensure that your workers SG WorkPass app AccessCode reflects their approval to be deployed for work and to facilitate arrangement for regular swab tests.",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "I have successfully submitted my manpower details but the Workpass app still comes out as red. Can I proceed to deploy my workers?",
        "answer": "The AccessCode factors in a few parameters, namely:",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    }
]